# **Matthew F Crooks**

Simi Valley, California | Cell: 818-448-3815 | mfcrooks@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Full Stack Developer experienced using frontend and backend technologies such as Ruby, Rails, Node, JavaScript, and React and a background in marketing. Industry knowledge of game development and design enabled me to successfully launch a video game product on Steam. As a developer, I bring strong collaborative and problem-solving skills to help companies achieve all tasks and goals given.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, SQL, PostGres, ActiveRecord, jQuery, JSON, NodeJS, React, Redux, NextJS, HTML, CSS, Restful APIs, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Python, Java, Wordpress, C#, Unity, Oracle, Object-Oriented Programming, Linux, Unix, Typescript, Certified AWS Cloud Practitioner

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## FlagNote - Github | Demo

A web-based note taking application specifically for pentesters and CTF events.

- Designed an interactive, efficient UI with RESTful routing using React-Redux.
- Developed Ruby on Rails API back-end to handle data persistence and respond to fetch requests.
- Applied custom Tailwind styling resulting in improved readability and use.

# Pantry-JS - Github | Demo

A single-page web app for tracking the food in your pantry.

- Applied jQuery and AJAX to asynchronously make GET and POST requests.
- Built an expandable project, with room to add new modules for recipes or grocery lists.
- Leveraged Rails backend API and PostGres for the database.

## Gamedev Manager - Github | Demo

A Sinatra based website for game developers to share their projects.

- Utilized ActiveRecord for storing information in a database.
- Developed expandable CRUD interface, allows for creating, reading, updating and deleting website content.
- Adhered to RESTful conventions; applied the MVC pattern.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### RogueWare LLC, Woodland Hills, CA

December 2012 - Present

Co-Founder

- Designed and developed a single-player video game.
- Launched successful Steam Greenlight campaign, FreeHolder, for sale online.
- Cultivated online presence with social media.

# Lyft, Los Angeles, CA

September 2015 - April 2020

Ride-Share Driver

- Maintained a 5.0 star rating with over 3000 rides.
- Transported passengers safely to desired destinations.

### L.H. Dottie Co., Commerce, CA

April 2010 - September 2013

Marketing Specialist

- Built product displays and established standards for the sales team to replicate in the field.
- Created marketing materials, including flyers and advertisements.
- Wrote and distributed press releases.

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School July 2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program

## University of California, Davis, Davis, CA

Bachelor of Science (BS), Psychology with a Biology emphasis